okay I'm gonna I have a present for
Spanish speakers tonight tango and
regalo para nuestros this couch
establish panda I wanted to teach this
meditation posture Winston is the poster
nemetes young okay we use it in DC I
very often
and I never teach the whole thing I
teach like two or three pieces and then
we stop so I'm gonna try especially for
our cool Latin American group no intent
that especial münster para nuestro grupo
de Latin America let's see if I can do
the whole poster tonight in our own
money in our money pay me so let's let's
go okay and I've only done it once in my
life
Sol Rachel I did it in 1998 land a
medicine to the center LMB she used to
be the director right sorry okay alright
and I translated the whole chart so I'm
gonna give you the translation after
tonight so first I'm going to talk about
some of the description on the two sides
Costello's then I'm gonna go through
every single thing in the human computer
with the top gear top Q thank you
we're gonna do a horse race vamos
central una carrera de caballo
that means the llama choice it talk fast
we try to finish a big thing in a small
amount of time
but can you we have a time limit on this
Jim 9:30 Oh dad I can do that okay
that's just a medium horse race okay all
right and I might have
although do the good luck can you see
all this number I put the numbers on the
chart okay
like I can't see it very well from here
okay
so those weren't on there I put them on
there I tried to make them look like the
car me yeah like this number one is
three maybe you're suspicious because
the numbers are not numbers but I didn't
want to destroy the woodcarving feeling
we cannot keep silence so here's what
the side says okay and this chart as I
mentioned before was designed by -
jongmin / - he's the teacher of the
current dynamometer maestro Dalai Lama
and he's the student of Campeche who
wrote the famous Lamia muscle memory
which we study in these retreats gets to
the amo semester Latinos we will spend
25 years on that but what was a pasar
about halfway finished
by Musco milometer if you want the next
installment come here in March March
21st I think Bobby sorry
Valley Valley that Beach is better than
Brazil ok and you can hear and he was
also the root Lama the heart Lama of my
teacher
is Lama de corazon de mayest and I think
he's the greatest writer in Tibetan
history much grander my story other
David his writing skill sorry that Paris
Philippi in that lamrim book especially
in this agreement no one knowing that's
the that's maybe the last great tibetan
book ever written and it's in in in pure
tibetan language and it's very beautiful
this has polluting more grandiose just
give you an idiomatic done okay now I'm
gonna just read you the sign it says all
the spiritual qualities quality is a
spirit but it's come from meditation
he says I cannot give you all the
benefits of meditation notice Paul Erdos
beneficios that I made us young but he
says any spiritual quality any spiritual
practice you undertake with your ability
to focus your mind becomes a much higher
Karma higher good kamma get uh believe
that okay and blend this condom Nagar
and quality that funny folk art a higher
yeah so usually we think our meditation
is supposed to do in the morning or
something like that
tomato soup on the colossus por las
mañana's but now he's talking about the
ability to focus on my knodel I believe
that time for and and he says anything
you do like you you are giving money to
poor people in you know different
countries yeah this is locust ecosystems
in there I can't the program not saying
oh you are teaching kids how to eat good
food or do yoga
en de los ninos como element Elsevier
non-commercial yoga what he says is the
Karma is higher if you are meditating in
the morning Karma's masala vada stand-up
or lasagna because your state of mind is
so beautiful look at the stuff in
Palestine in a Moscow first he says try
to find the six conditions which are
help you to reach good meditation we
talked about them are decent and time
for Darla says condition is Cassidy
tomatoes vamos hacer que estas then he
says try to learn about the five
problems of meditation nobody say intent
aprender a circle a las cinco problemas
americium and the eight solutions las
ocho solution which you guys learned a
long time ago
there's Apprendi Aramis a mucho tiempo
this morning esta mañana
if recovery and he says those five
problem aids solution teaching that
called Club Russian guys heard this
morning is a sensational Cinco problemas
soluciones killed gurupada Rado the
Roseate - esta mañana
he says he want to know who who they
came from
Giddins aware the the that can be no
they come from my trail and then they
might drea and he mentions here tandem J
MIDI and Ave Bunga it means how to
separate the middle way from the two
extremes here mention aquí como se para
El Camino medio de los dos extremist so
you studied all those subjects like how
to lose the object to do so so stammers
como como perder el objeto sleepy mind
busy mind mental Irma La demente Akita
ocupada
failing to do something when the smoke
alarm goes off let's sleep tomorrow
Uranus arena correction cuando ellos
hacen RL detector de mo
what was the last one for $0 settled or
lettuce
yeah staying within New York accents
again that's a New York accent
twist your mouth oh yeah if you didn't
[Laughter]
if the mentation going smooth don't
check don't don't use your smoke alarm
to take the battery okay and then he
talks about the corrections cerca de las
elecciones develop a deep belief in the
benefits like that's the four things
with the high school okay
and he talks about shinjang which means
if you get good at meditation cousin if
you could cause if there were debates
going on normally it does you know it
feels like somebody giving you a good
massage siesta como si are interim when
massage I heard the same thing happens
with yoga but I didn't experience it
personally it's good check hello miss
what's a second experiment if you do it
a lot you starts to feel good III don't
know but they say that all right then he
talks about timba the cowboy rope
bringing the object back to your mind
[Music]
and we're gonna go through that in the
chart so I'm not gonna then it says
guess what there's nine mental states
that you go through from annotations
Mentalist por las cuales process at
reversal emeritus you guys studied that
a long time
stairs to the aaron hace mucho diem this
morning early esta mañana temprano most
of you were asleep during then something
we didn't cover which were going to
cover tomorrow probably is called six
modes and four kinds of focus size model
see cuatro tipos and forty almost a
quarry mañana then he quotes a book
called the human in BO the essence of
the middle way master the elephant of
the mind my elephant elementary step by
step in this way paso de esta manera the
elephant wants to go the wrong way
the fantastically poor unlucky Wakaba so
you're gonna have to drive a stake into
the ground and tie him a tener que
clarinets taka and then a peaceful
camera the state is the object of your
meditation
like I said okay and the rope that saga
is that bringing pulling the mind back
to the object then you're gonna need the
iron hook Sara called the pan
if you ever saw how they drive it how
you drive an elephant CME's DoCoMo
manikandan elephant you have some hooks
special hooks and you put them in a very
sensitive place in the ear that's how a
small person can force an elephant to go
the way they want to go in pequeno para
so he says use the iron hook of your
wisdom i'm julia cerro de las navas
ludia so children purchased said I want
to I'm gonna use that elephant from that
famous book from India for this picture
I mean the yellow cherry caballo sorry
elephant la famosa libro de indias St
MaxEnt case
I'm gonna then he just we're gonna talk
about everything in the in the poster
itself so I'm not gonna repeat what he
says that was a lot of Lucas than their
poster as he cannot repeat it
yeah and then he ended with a poem I
mean at one point and it mentions the
sponsor who paid for the and he
dedicated the Karma to that person's
father persona
okay and that this block print was
finished in 1967 this isn't ice yet it
was carved in a refugee camp I knew many
of the monks from that camp many many
died about from my monastery 99% I chose
monk as this example they me monasterio
already adore delano in time for siento
and the 1% they trained me alright okay
here we go
and Jana will you do it I'll say number
one did you try to find number one
Noren and it also can help you okay okay
this is called save Joppa by the way the
carving is very unclear and it took me
many hours but I figured it out so it
means okay you got a long way to go okay
the top of the chart is perfect
meditation
/ - there even a lot tablets my
imperfecta this one is the first of the
nine stages what is it mr. sir primero
that was my bathtub Pasquale's yeah just
start thinking about me this afternoon
see so lock yourself inside in your they
stepped out of it you just put the mind
on the object for this to maintain in
the local this morning we were doing a
special meditation estamos haciendo
namah it does you know special called
tongue man
tongue you take away people's problems
you give them happiness problems
personas he lives and we were learning a
special way to do it for yourself then
your future self is almost different
from your present self and we were
sending help to our staff who has a
difficult meeting with the past in the
afternoon to discuss my race Mukunda
difficile con su trabajo para discutir
so mentos then we are sending good
energy to me so I don't get angry
[Music]
ok ok
there you go yeah it's a chamber that's
bringing the mind back that's the cowboy
bringing the mind back to the and it's
an elephant hole you see it's a chain
with a hook on it in this in the monks
hand in the left hand it's two metal
hooks so number two is timber ok no
matter loss is temper what's number
three yeah that's another kind of hook
that elephant drivers use is a throw
gancho caboose an escape
- elephant is and it represents smoke
alarm it represented the tech turtle our
mother okay so the mark he put his mind
on the object as he came upon the cement
and a libretto and now he's gonna use
his two tools susan test for work but
okay driving the black crazy elephant
guess what that is para para manejar el
elefante local negro your mind
then he's got these two tools okay in
his right hand is the smoke alarm when
you start to think about churros up
inside when you go dulce de leche what's
the other thing
alpha this is the ultimate yocha yocha
supra caramel man talk about it am i
talking about that oh yeah when you lose
the meditation and you start talking
about hoarder Carlos alpha 4s I should
bring some tomorrow I'm gonna bring some
I was Theresa gave me a box but I was
sacrificed that I made over a
significant so it has two weapons Aramis
this one called shishun smoke alarm
astonishing we said watch from this
Lancia part of your mind is watching the
rest of your mind to see if there's a
meditation problem and if they if it
detects a problem is allotted texture
then it will use the hook which we call
we're gonna call bringing the object
back
Robo sorrel gancho case
so those are his two tools first one
smoke alarm
detect the problem the inner mind
problem in lamented you lost keys lock
you lost your subject you start to think
about that's the smoke alarm chamber has
to like wait what was I talking about
before I guess then you bring the mind
back so which hand is he going to use
first for $20 but raise your hand
Quailman nobles are primero for $20 11
it's up to you nor to right hand he used
the right hand first $20 opium our pork
a regime a porky
why is his right hand so does heavens a
novel yeah there's a smoke detector in
the right hands he assumed that thick
toward a woman a mother nature
then he bring it back with the left hand
20 it's a $30 answer to a $20 question
that's the best kind of answer who gives
$30 to $20
not moving perfecto perfecto oh yeah
okay now can you go back to the whole
picture
how many times does the road twist
cuantas veces that curve alchemy no one
- its kind of five or six okay now there
are six powers in meditation I didn't
but at each curve in the road going up
to schemata Corwin El Camino para
Shibata there's a new power you gain a
new power of Genesis no put it
so where's number four as you can
understand the middle cuatro yeah now
that that counts as the first curve of
the road okay the beginning of the road
counts is number one so what's happening
at this one sake your teacher is
teaching you in the class about
meditation by talking talking to Maya
strata stance on yendo en la clase Allah
platter - okay
and he's he or she is giving you
instructions about your meditation
object yellow at the stand and
instruction assessor cadet - over here -
America's young okay
and based on that you can reach the
first mental state Eva southern and
super second sorry primera state of
mental which is what is number one here
just put your mind on the meditation of
a solopreneur to maintain a limitation
but if you don't have a teacher to give
you a meditation object you cannot start
meditating in buddhism forget it
ferrocene assume a stroke at the
doorknob caterham it does yo not play
the same parameter will be the law in
the Buddhism oh okay now never fire or
no butter Cinco it says the elephant is
your mind an elephant is to mint then
look at the elephant
above it the elefante Arriba the ears
are turning white the solar system will
blanket the one above that the whole
head is white yesterday la cabeza it's
important okay
now the black color 100% black case
that's important to colored Negro
represents sleepy mind sleeping
what's the two great methods to develop
good sleep in mind doing number one eat
a lot number two don't get in asleep
then try to meditate then your elephant
will be black black means sleepy now
there's a meditation detailed that I
didn't talk to you about we can say
distraction distraction and busy mind
and they are not exactly the same
distraction means your mind go to the
other object like it went to the yojo it
went to the alfajores
destruction escape to meant a safe way
our truck at the safe well Jojo but busy
mine is just kind of a bad mental habit
you keep thinking about different things
but distraction is your mind actually
goes strongly to another object esta
pasando muchos caused us ok instruction
let's get to meant this about
technically technique commented the
monkey is distraction el Chango s
destruction actually moving to another
object okay their choices the movie
Repetto then the black color yell :
aggro is busy mine
and I you can see up higher the monkey's
head turns white that represents the
hair falling out of that of the of the
great meditators right JB just kidding
you kill me I thought you a nice person
who said guys he looks just like John
Brady Jane this is a personal sacrifice
a wake up lady okay
and number seven numero siete
[Music]
yeah there's seven now right above seven
there's is something it looks like the
last time you spilled spaghetti on the
floor who study well I see a palace a
master spaghetti but it's not noodles
okay it's supposed to be fire fire
supona gets big flame okay and this
represents how hard do you have to work
to fix the meditation how much effort
you have to make you fix a meditation
center content of the test case for SAR
para regular meditation and you can see
the fires are getting smaller and
smaller and you go up the road so every
much but can you see my spec is mental a
subiendo por el camino how much fire in
meditation state number 8 for $20 2004 1
el esta la tapa demitasse en el estado
mental numero Ocho de velas here's the
question how much fire it means how much
effort you have to make in the
meditation at state number 8 aqui esta
la pregunta quantify go quanto quiere
decir cuantos where so tienes que hacer
no fire no it has to be less good than
nine but I think it's supposed to be
about doing anything because I don't
maintain it
yeah I think you said it right maybe in
the first few minutes in the first five
minutes seven minutes you have to fight
a little bit with your mind
primero Cinco minutos tienes que luchar
contra to me the fires pretty Sparkle if
I was muy pequeño okay and then what's
the difference level nine for zero
dollars but if I had support anyway yeah
no effort the eye eye eyelids closed
during the amenities ninguna sports way
lokasya right okay so I I hope when he
reaches number nine there won't be any
fire espero que cuando el concern even
number eleven vienna gum flavor so that
also represents how strong you have to
use the two tools as a representative in
k-town salazar Mientus smoke alarm and
cowboy broke a lot mother a lot so the
back arrow okay number eight numero Ocho
this is called thinking about what the
teacher said about meditation in the
class in your cabin esto significa
pensara psychological maestro circle
animators yawn end to qivana okay and
that will help you reach the second of
the nine meditations I lost my Estados
they may eat asean
ii military then this term is Sehun
verse that Allah made me understand and
then second meditation state right the
style that made us you can keep your
mind on that dead long
so whereas men tener tu mente number
eight that's thinking about the class
that you got from meditation inside a
circle like classic economic decision
based on that solid Nestle you can hold
the object for a whole string of mantras
Austin area locator portal now Rhonda
amantha's don't do the mattress during
the meditation then you're thinking
about mantras you know but it means take
about that long on money home we decided
professor Stanley Bundy decided 90
seconds probably check the Sanskrit and
see okay
number nine yeah there's a little
Tibetan number two there which
represents the second mental state which
is okay lah what's the difference
between eight and nine in the chart
number eight no matter what you are
thinking about what your teacher told
you in the class then the result of that
is number nine you can keep your mind
for some all right yeah we're gonna
we're doing good Tim you said well but I
have to finish my oh yeah I'm sorry for
the Mexico hair that's gonna be 11:30 I
can't unsay me I give you permission
don't meditate in the morning
it would be almost midnight when you go
to sleep basura Cosima we are not
Chicano so another mission yeah okay
number 10 no matter the s okay the
elephant's yarmulke
LF the Israelis understand the Jewish
people wear a special hat right elephant
has one here that represents your
sleepiness is starting to improve you
are you are the black color is going
away a little bit represent a get to
mental or milanesa maker on 43rd color
Negros mpesa Vanessa Paquito and I
didn't teach you this subject yet it's
called Salcha and nature say self
generation yesterday I wouldn't sell
nature okay and we'll talk about it
tomorrow it's on your homework I think
cell cha now listen this is difficult or
escuchen Salcha means how clear is the
meditation right cell means to be clear
no choice that difficult word that means
condition so Jason if you get thanked
lettuce tomatoes young Charles Apollo
åkesson if you cut condition so now this
is very difficult in the study of
meditation it's this movie fishing in
the studio made us young and this is why
the meditation teacher who talked about
meditation in the class will say look
you just have to go to your cabin
and try to figure it out okay yeah I
can't show you inside your own mind you
have to go to your retreat cabin and you
have to you have to find what I'm
talking about it's the spot low quality
my estimators you enter a series of the
Tina scale to a touka vanya attendance
cavity where they look at the soil and
Esquivel so for $100 for CN dollar this
it's okay it's okay
I gotta ask my wife they won't get any
esposa
don't worry they won't get it Cooper I
never offer a lot of money
sometimes one guy messes me up
what does clarity mean Salcha what does
clarity mean in meditation Gerson if you
cut Clara dad and meditation now if I
say your meditation is very clear what
do I mean
see they go get to meditation as my
Clara camera Fiero it means you can see
the object very clearly saying if you
gotta pass when I look at okay I meant
now when people ask the burner for his
opinion he said I need to understand
your question a little bit more gravitas
opinion the second pokémon
what becomes clear during soldier okay
say what about Clara Durant a searcher
but meditation object the object of your
mind your mind hypercard on you you
splitting the money or something some
corruption going on so it doesn't mean
how clear the object nice fifty dollars
so far
go see if you can love head towards that
quality of your concentration beautiful
significant deterrent yeah
okay yeah in the study of meditation in
el estudio de la meditation clarity like
clarita things are clearer than Clara's
it doesn't mean that the this afternoon
you you can see the color of their eyes
and how what's in their nose and things
like that are very cool or de los ojos
see Kevin throw this one at ease
I'll show you clarity that's why I said
not cloudy already I went to the movies
in in China it's very fun we all seen
them Jeana it's when the popcorn is Vida
you sugar and song and you know it's
like pineapple on your pizza it's it's
another Chinese thing and then we go to
the movie they take my kids take me ten
lang each and I'm Arjun accent and like
tomorrow then everybody's talking and
they're watching the movie the guy falls
in love with the girl the guy is chasing
the girl for a long time understand
sitting here for at the end then and
everybody's eating okay maybe there's
some tension between the guy in the girl
but finally they get stuck in a closet
together but often are met the second
night or Alison closes in they're
looking in their eyes comments office
and then the the live starting again you
know
if you look at the people's face in the
movie theater at that moment cemitas el
rastro de las personas and escena en ese
momento the popcorn is here that's tacky
and then everyone's done that's clarity
it's all that I'm not kidding I'm not
kidding okay what's this observing that
stuff mind on the objects sometimes
movie popcorn movie Palomita película
follow me here's clarity it doesn't mean
how clear is the movie it doesn't mean
the movies in focus or something it
means good meditation mind is bright and
happy and excited like in that moment in
the movie you want to know what is
shinjang what is physical and mental
ecstasy in meditation location ecstasy
mentally physical medicine it's exactly
that moment in the movie everyone in the
series like it's a sacrament as a
momentum as película stars and their sin
is done except one guy had got a cell
phone call he's like why I accept her
all right that's clarity now a job we
didn't finish nature nature means how
strong is the connection how how how
much is the head on the pillow is the
head on the pillow and if you can't get
them for testing a connection is the
meditation resting on the object is
there a connection
are you not connection between the
object and the mind is it staying there
may means to stay nature means how well
is the mind staying on the element so
the yarmulke on the elephant's head I
see que la cabeza del elephant that I
have one that I got it in Israel people
like me we like them alive it represents
represent his soldier and his nature is
increasing
this is increasing as to think remain
Tondo and keeping on the object is
increasing what's decreasing guess that
sleepiness sleep in mine ok got it
esta diciendo it's a cool chart right
and those of people in the room who did
[Applause]
each one of them had to build their own
cabin with their own money and their own
hands god I will know that yes - okay
construe it's appropriate Cabana
consistency and they donate them to you
after they finish accept sir Rodney and
her husband daemon accept them accept
them they donate two houses on the
scousers
and lama divorce house where her house
is like big enough for three houses so
by the way llama Dora I'd like to
introduce her present
she lives in Israel I remember she went
to Israel she's the first ACI student in
Israel she's very lonely today and she
started to translate the ACI courses yet
reduceed law school so they see and she
start to teach one person then two
people now how many people are acontece
personas many hundreds of people no okay
[Applause]
and she finished the 10,000 pages
translation into Hebrew and then they're
building a diamond mountain in Israel
[Music]
[Applause]
when I start a one-year budget on a
retreat what what month soon they
finished other diamond weight courses in
January they will finish all 1836
courses okay okay yeah and they're gonna
invite people from Arab people
Palestinian people so there's a war
between Israel and for many years so
they in their retreat center the people
come together yeah we should
so half the people are Muslim half the
people are Jewish and they're all ACI
cooperating very nice tang copper and if
you'd like to make a donation for their
retreat cabins not on ASEAN para su
centers Cavanaugh's appetito
she won't say no yeah no I said no and
she has to leave early tomorrow morning
she came to help us make the new nuns
because you need nuns to maintenance but
if you interested to help with this
retreat sinister and which I think will
help to make peace in the Middle East
surpass and many oriented then talk to
do something yeah you want to add they
only need further assistance in comedian
less thank you
now that is a lot of materials
translated into Hebrew of the ACI plus
other materials now a group of students
from our Center is has begun a major
project of translating into Arabic
there's billions of Arabs
[Applause]
by the way she had a lot of obstacles it
wasn't easy okay to go from one student
to many hundred students to a muchos
tequila's not for not a fascist they
read a witness to the entire cientos it
wasn't easy it wasn't smooth not fast
enough but she's tough and she keep
trying keep trying keep trying
you see you think now it's a largest
Buddhist group in Israel so it's not
always easy but you have to be tough
alright Andy are you ready number 12
okay
[Music]
that's 12 where's the 11th isn't it does
okay
did I do it I didn't do 11 oh I'm sorry
you're right okay let's go to 11 okay
most of them I don't see what does it
look like to you it's on the left of the
of the red yeah what's it look like
yeah peach tree cafe no it looks like a
food right Marisa come on the fruit and
this means the things that you think
about
it's a churro it's a hotel it's a
panchak - it's a alfajores okay it's
something you enjoy these foods to eat
okay you are so your meditation is
disturbed
that's at least right by this beautiful
food or beautiful churros or beautiful
enchiladas which I got tonight huh so
you made those key to western audience
getting a teacher you should be a cook
yesterday cocinero okay both loves us
okay
so that represents the things the
distractions okay the present Ella's
districts and we're gonna see them do
you see those two things that look like
targets about 15 represent Jimi Hendrix
represent an IG me Hendrix
those are Tibetan it means my iTunes
Spotify okay Spotify - okay and it means
distraction to sound so needle
alright so now that's taste right the
fruit is taste
how many sense objects you have five big
ones five physical ones
so there's four the taste I stop there's
four music and the mirror is traditional
symbol for things you can see that's the
traditional symbol there should be smell
and there should be touch maybe it says
max to the hooks peach maybe oh yeah
yeah yeah I think that's one of the
maybe silk then they say tastes and
smells are connected in most cases let's
see if we find some more okay the same
compromise mass where where I sign
oh I say yeah maybe yeah
above 13 could be let's see as we go
let's see through anyway these are the
objects of your senses sohcahtoa lost
and when you get distracted your mind
goes to those things tries to mentor
psoriasis okay now I think we're on
number 12
vamos a numero dos a and that's bringing
the mind back to the object
I think like if the monk is using his
his smoke alarm and his cowboy laughs on
the elephant 13 yeah this is when he
come patching the gap it's this combo
Partch and/or loss Waco's it's number
three you bring the mind back quickly
and close - close it up okay 14 oh
there's a new guy it's a rabbit he's a
black color he's riding on the elephant
[Music]
okay he's a rabbit you can see his ears
what ifs okay and that represents
spacing out during meditation look look
your body is perfect represented get our
tacoma we don't let it touch you
everybody wants to take a picture you
look so good in your meditation toma una
foto de estas but actually you just
think about nothing else and acerca de
nada
okay no meditation object of subtle
sleepiness big sleepiness that's easy
you are snoring if you're but this one
pero esta and thinking about nothing
that's very dangerous because it feels
like meditation
it says muy peligroso por que se sienta
consistory okay so that he added the
rabbit CK yeah great
and that's spacing out subtle dumbass
yes
[Music]
now the monkey in front of the elephant
elephant which is looking back at the
mind now his head is turning around it's
probably some anatole yoga thing that
represents you are able to catch your
mind after object is kept as the catcher
tu mente cuando se valet libretto and
you are able to bring it back like this
okay then you come back to the good
translation
we gotta Kyrie Kyrie can you help us
Changi Joe tanto
Changi talk again southern monkey is
remembering what he's supposed to do
ahead got a little bit white the monkey
generally the black monkey is busy
momentum uyoku pala but now he's looking
back at the meditation maybe I should go
back to the meditation alright number 16
number of the se says guess nine stages
guess yeah you are hanging on to the
mess is the quality good no but I'm not
gonna lose the object anchor
I'm hanging on to my future afternoon
stuff are you like this in the movie la
película is it bright is it clear is it
happy no it's a war I'm hanging on to
the object I'm hanging on to the object
okay but it doesn't feel very fun
buddies progress you are making progress
progress okay so that's number sixteen
and there's a small Tibetan four in that
little tent and translators know this is
where you put numbers in scriptures you
carve a little okay number what are we
on yeah what's going on in it means your
smoke alarm is extremely well developed
so your smoke alarm get to the picked or
the most irregular is extremely well
developed it's tremendous okay
number 18 numero de Acho it's the
monkeys improving okay Chang was Tommy :
the numbers supposed to relate to the
monkey half his body's okay it means
your mind is not switching to other
objects anymore okay and cannot after
that you won't have a problem
losing the object and thinking of
another round thing okay let's play a
certain air
probably mother predators and okay okay
number 19 me and me and Kari are having
fun okay Carly where's 19 the
understudies enjoy you wanna somewhere
around 20 and guess what what's going on
what's going on is that monkeys in a
tree just and honourable oh it is a
monkey reaching for a fruit yes soon
changuk is that another cancer on the
fruit very similar to the Wheel of Life
main number which think doctors to live
life number eight give a simple this
monkey in the tree reaching for a fruit
has a different meaning and it's very
important for you guys yes more
importantly status okay now I was
noticing that diamond ring $10,000
diamond ring they just the gang and she
ten just left it up here so for three
days or something Suganya equity coma
for three you know and I'm from I'm in
the diamond business I'm like what yes
your mantis adjust our si como then I
remember who's here recollectionist aqui
this is the safest group of people to
leave a diamond ring in the whole world
these people are so cool they're gonna
put a second banner in there I know he's
gonna achieve me you're gonna put
another so people in this room like you
are already good people
sometimes I'm embarrassed you know but
they're already better than me so your
problem is not that you are gonna do bad
things you're not gonna steal the
diamond I seek a su problema nose kiss
away in that robot Ilana diamante your
problem is you have so many good things
you want to do well problemas que tienen
tantas cosas buenas Kyra Nasser and you
don't know which one is better you know
serving quite let's make
right that's our problem problem we try
to do all of them Veronica's taught us
don't try to do another good project
just do the ones you have make them good
so our problem is prioritizing our good
deeds problem as priori priorities are
Nostra's wellness acciones which good
deed is more important than the other
good team well when acciones más
importante que la otra when action and
in meditation in meditation
halfway through your meditation
development it becomes an obstacle to
try to reach a second good goal during
the same meditation
se vuelve one obstacle at retarder
concern Segundo meta Duran telemedicine
so you are doing Tong and on future
Mike
Asik estas haciendo tonglen and then
Michael footer and then you're like well
I think I'll do emptiness on the room
where I'm in and that's you know that's
a good karma yes at some point karma but
during the meditation on tone man it's a
bad karma pero durante la metas yonder
tonglen assume al karma it's a
distraction it's not Easter eggs
you are hurting your meditation choose
choose a meditation object it's kind of
kilometers you at the beginning of the
meditation session al principio de la
sección de meditation and do not change
it halfway through in a lot cumbias
maybe you think of oh this thing also
very beautiful
Jesus Tommy MPs oyster esta means we are
muscle and it's true yes it's also very
beautiful it's estimated more muscle but
if you split the meditation it's not
single point anymore
barks the famous to burn thing cincuenta
dólares but I own the chhoti but I know
my family if you give it to me I want it
in Tibetan seem a lot Karen DeWitt dunno
you're gonna give me $50 cancel the back
answer then say hey Alice wants to try
okay wait wait
go ahead don't send your pet cheetah
know what you try nice
i needa with two points you can't sew
anything
what do you mean significa
if you choose a meditation object at the
beginning of the meditation time don't
change halfway to dodging our principal
elevators
can be inanimate even if it looks cool
and even if it's a beautiful thing of
course it's it you guys everything you
do is beautiful so choose the more
important one I think it's important if
you have trouble choosing is it an
improbably my skokie and your teacher is
always the greatest meditation object
period my asteroid makoto kilometers
your your parents people who taught you
in the school your your priest in the
church or your imam and these are data
if you if you're not sure which one is
better go back to your teacher that's
the most powerful karma karma Moscow so
in this picture which I can't see it
very well but I guess there's a monkey
reaching for a second fruit a second
fruit nest a máquinas a point where
movie Emperor soon changuk is that a nut
Castle on my second the food and you
have to work past that it can escape
okay Tim get am I allowed to take a
break maybe the people in Latin America
also want to go to the refrigerator
right now theme us tomorrow break Eli
Canton Latino money cut up in America
point out referee you mean or you want
to just go straight or not say Obama
straight say either do what do you guys
go first people want to go straight
through another half-hour raise your
hand I can't think Achilles I eat people
who want to go to the bathroom raise
your hand fifty-fifty okay 10-minute
break Batson all right here we go back
to the elephant wasn't what number had
to do next 20 our King did no one else
together baby hmm
we are working hard on smoke alarm in
number 20
it's the most oh I found the little cone
there that they throw they won one day
Numan away that's his right hand right
he's right hand
and he's making good progress yes the
sin nobody ever won progress oh and
almost no distraction cuz it's in
distraction so which animal became white
candy melts over your blank oh yeah see
the monkey is killing white chunko
chunko is almost white in front of the
month hasta casablanca and not much
effort the flame is small you know
muchos for so la flama stop again yeah
not not it doesn't take too much hard
work in the meditation now number 20 is
a new idea which I didn't teach you yet
no matter wait this one on my way there
candle essence in yellow it's called
sang to Papa
when your meditation feels a little bit
down like slightly depressed comida and
it feels heavy it's just in the pestle
and forget the movie you know it's like
watching a bad movie or en la película
and what can we do inside to brighten
after my chemo so Sarah then throw para
eliminar lament then they say think of
someone you love okay anything kaypea
necessary cardigan cameras think of
someone you know and then automatically
the mind will the also the posture will
you know Oh
automatic a meat elemental a posterior
Anika
you know and then it's a inside way to
lift up the mind I'll think of someone
like your parents who've been very kind
to you but that's the antidote for
feeling little heavy or stand in a
meditation centre Paris until como
pasado el pasado America see alright I'm
gonna change something here hang on yeah
no okay somebody tell me what's
happening in mental state number five
controlling the mind
I don't remember myself okay okay here
it is no more big sleepiness you know I
meant me
oh yeah so in the chart in that table
number 21 in the middle wait do you know
no more sleepiness should be the
elephant is all white oh good yeah I
used to have subtle sleepiness pacing
pacing now okay say again number five is
sorry twenty-one i I'm guessing it's the
elephant I don't know which one I think
behind the one behind I think and so
half of the darkness is gone the obvious
darkness is gone sleep in mind is gone
mentor me let us say you know spacing
out is not gun 22 represents peace in
the mind the mind is peaceful and the
quotation in the book is no more big
danger of spacing um Graham peligro the
courtesy it means there is a small
danger so can you believe his body
stubborn people hate people hate the
people okay but not the big problem no
my son Graham problem not a big problem
okay good 23 no matter when did dress
what's going on it's supposed to be you
are willing to work hard at your
meditation okay
sisupala clearance as for Saturday and
tomatoes you you are willing to do the
work to make it perfect
Jesus el trabajo para celibate effect
oftentimes in Buddhism OSS in the Rudy's
MO as the obstacle becomes smaller and
smaller it takes more effort to kill it
okay like to to kill the obvious
laziness it takes not so big effort
lockira oh yeah not all my dentist for
so but sudden laziness takes a lot of
devotion you have to keep working
working working which I was the last 10
percent of spiritual progress takes 90
percent of the time es por ciento the
progress the spirit are the dominant
force in night time okay alright that's
23 I don't see anything that looks like
effort there
general nie Casa de si como is where so
yeah it is the current frame yeah it's
the curve okay you're right Stanley
bundu 24 numero veinticuatro the mind
has become completely quiet mr.
completamente Silencio and you see his
explanation got longer and he said no
more subtle sleepiness which is spacing
out The Economist mental Urmila so till
cascade our toledo and no more subtle
busy mind for twenty dollars in no man's
mental capacity Vivian you understand
you guys are not gonna try make some
money no more subtle days in mind no
more subtle busy mind I must men tell us
what's a sudden busy mind she needs
money to get home Sarah busy mind ten in
ten either issue mayor Johnson
yeah mayo hotel the whole truth a toe
and things in the drum has a desk you
eat the end in Syria Huijin there's no
education I want to know subtle busy
mind what is it Yaroslavl
that means day acappella so what's it
feel like What's it feel like
Thomas Sen should I make up in the shop
yeah okay you got it water under the
eyes that's like a sixteen dollar and so
at 24
no more subtle this in mind and who's
white who's white Cooper a suit the
monkey is right
the monkey is mr. Blanco we cleaned out
that even the Sun epitome inclusive and
the text says the carving says even if
it comes for a second you start to think
about all the busy things you have to do
right yeah Tech studies say inclusive
coming up on Segundo business up and
tell us Costas getting scarcer you just
like he you know he's gone so you know
it's not big fight not we have a
meditate sooner quit and just kick it
out of the mic okay got it
by this time your meditation is so
powerful and sweet potatoes it's the 709
meditation levels even if you start to
feel like you're gonna you are going to
think about all the things you have to
do you can just put all right number 25
he says I don't know his explanation got
long because your master
the elephant lost all his black
fanta / do total a partner and how about
a monkey jicama and el Chango yeah good
the disappeared this the disappear
monkey muy bien el Chango is a palace I
mean the monkey disappear okay I'm a
little bit tired okay dad none is so
hard to make a nun the mom takes like
ten minutes
yes the nun took like five hours sick or
maybe that's why the okay see us that
it's important that the monkeys is out
of the picture now it's important
Chango Emma stay in lesson and you're
starting to get single point
concentration in stem personnel
concentration only ponder and to fix all
the problems minimum effort right almost
automatic not quite on a regular todos
problemas is casseon automatic onus for
some meaning and we saw at level a
number 26 he has the monk has single
pointed mind a kagra
latina concentration upon twelve egg
Kagura he sing into the object says to
American elevator after a few minutes of
work at the beginning después de unos
minutos de trabajo el comienzo okay
number 27 and Stanley point out it's the
curve is the image the curve is the
image the Mara when TC attack America
Stanley like kuru buyers like making and
this is called getting used to
meditation getting like
you can tell the people who do yoga on
their mats are dirty and worn out
if acostumbrado elevators your knees
come on I can take a muchacha viscous
with yoga mats will show ya the stuff so
just before you come to the mountain
trade your new yoga mat for an old one
Monty
compared to Matt porn on my polynomial
Cooper done big guest I will think
you're working hard at your yoga and at
all your mat is so worn out here give me
give me a new okay you understand so 27
represents he's good friends with his
meditation see they meet every day no
matter when TC at this cuz mind amigo
con su Sammy has amazed us he has a good
strong habit
number nine sorry it's 28 in English he
finally looks like he is walking where
is his hook and his master coming he
doesn't need them anymore
ya know necesita if it ain't broken
don't fix it she know start with that
yeah that's okay I'm just saying he
doesn't need those two toes he should
start not using them don't overuse okay
now that's 28 she's supposed to be the
master level SE supone que se me horny
well that's level 9 assess and evaluate
supposed to be were finished supone que
quitar minimis no no now you have to go
to schemata no not part Irish amicus o
shamaton is 2019 no way and yeah we
caught shaman and he's sitting he's
controlling his mind now he's riding on
his mind control on the cement Testament
and oh cement and shemitah is means the
preliminary stage of the first from
where you can see emptiness from that
platform summit doesn't
like a preliminary raynella format on
donessa plataforma Parramatta and
schemata de pasión apassionata means
perfect meditation now you can see
emptiness directly if you start to see
two things happen and during shamaton
two things happen those kasih sudah
schemata the body feels unbelievable
like they say it feels like cotton piece
of cotton soft piece of cotton your body
is super comfortable that's 34 super
it's like you are flying in the air you
feel like you can fly when you sit on
your cushion from one hour it feels like
you're getting a massage from my yoga
teacher she was teaching me and some
other people how to do adjustment and
she's a great yoga master yes I saw her
in China and you go like this
and she goes you put her in a headstand
she goes and it's like she's eating ice
cream or sometimes you know twist my
[Music]
so that's a the monk feels like he's
flying the physical body in meditation
in shemitah' feels like you know
fantastic Mohammed associated fun 31 is
called mental meditation pleasure 30 is
called physical meditation 20 you know
selfless el physico
for you a chain well when you get to
shamatari passion in intense physical
pleasure and mentally plus el physico
intense 32 numero trente those Vipassana
and shemitah joining together be passion
is schemata say wounded and with your
sword of fire con tu s Paulo de fuego
which is seeing emptiness directly
koalas Percival avec we are direct and
you can cut the Wheel of Life
at the root link number 1
Allah is being cool alone so that
flaming sword is the 33 or so what's
better than man ok so 33 means it just
becomes a way of life
no Trent I try scientific a solo say
still la vida the direct recession
emptiness begins to have effect on your
life
perception director of a karate an
effect in the kitchen in la cocina yeah
immediately you remember the husband
says you're sitting you're already like
haha I forgot you're already thinking
about not yelling at your kids anymore
ok
Spence and agra tala two sequels No Mas
your pan power is perfect
de la pluma is perfect that's after
perfect meditation and emptiness it's
just a spasm a dozen perfectly back with
a path of habituation where do you reach
Path number three by the way I'm gonna
stop in one minute
tres por cierto apparent where you reach
Path number three under cancel on your
choice of dress I knew him in meditation
by the way there's a there's a school
that sense for certain escuela kadhi say
all going up through pass all connect
our borders in the past are only doing
meditation from terrace cuando está en
el camino so selling solid meditation
you can God you cannot go from got a to
God day you have to be in meditation
then got a got a para got a here
meditation para Sun got in here
meditation but it's on how here
meditation yeah you have to be in
meditation - meditation is like the
ladder rung okay last so anyway to me
that last fire still some effort right
but I mean si with Tim of well okay so
forth path el cuarto Sendero path of
habituation it's a neuronal a bit to us
use what you saw directly in emptiness
okay who's a lot a Vista director
mentally he's aware who salad on there
it's gonna offer $100 but you yeah
perfect answer let's bust up a free
prophy answer okay I'd like to stop
there okay
I have I have not taught the whole chart
to anybody for 25 years they'll elect a
completely asynchronous so what's your
job I seek equality su trabajo teacher
correctly to other people in sending
love correctamente and I'll give you in
the next stair to I'll give you the
translation of each piece all the pieces
is ready I think we can improve it
slightly
he didn't mention what's going on so I'd
like to add it to the in I'll add it in
parentheses you know it's my I added it
so it's not the it's not the Thomas
teacher but he just says like
controlling the mind we don't know what
it mean so I'd like to add from the
other homework I was teaching you what's
the meaning of those nine names well
it's a significant oh this was my
Vietnam brace okay and ie are you ready
relevancy in their body some years into
my token and ah-choo ah-choo ah-choo
you know come the
the Sun is a song she sang mission to me
la comida partial